SAMUEL R. TORRES

torressam333@gmail.com https://torressam333.github.io/samuel2020

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Creative and pragmatic programmer dedicated to creating and building high quality web applications using client side and server-side programming. Determined to integrate knowledge, education and experience to produce efficient, logically sound and interactive web applications.

EDUCATION

BACHELORS OF ARTS, CRIMINAL JUSTICE California State University San Bernardino — 2010-2014

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - COMPUTER SCIENCE WEB DEVELOPMENT:
EMPHASIS - JAVA/OPEN SOURCE
Palomar College, San Marcos — 2017-2019

PROGRAMMING KNOWLEDGE/SKILLS

Languages/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery/jQuery UI, RESTful API's, Responsive Web Design, PHP 5 & 7, MSSQL and MySQL. Experience working with with Bootstrap 4, SASS, Node.js and VCS (Git). Experience in Web/Hybrid app development. I am also familiar with Amazon Web Services. Knowledge and experience coding using Design Patterns, OOP and SOLID principles. Knowledge of the MVC methodology. Experienced Windows and Debian based linux user. Comfortable with CLI as well as GUI's.

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Dean's List Award, GPA of 4.0, California State University San Bernardino - 2013 Dean's List Award, GPA of 4.0, California State University San Bernardino - 2014 4.0 GPA, Palomar College - 2017 - 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

GOODWILL OF CENTRAL AND NORTHERN ARIZONA — 2019 - PRESENT

- Upgrade and maintain existing legacy applications.
- Provide design and code application architecture plans for current and future projects.
- Use both client side and server side languages to build and maintain intranet applications.
- Use various technologies and languages to maintain all web applications used by the business.

SAMUEL R. TORRES

torressam333@gmail.com (909) 531-1233

LIABILITY AND WORKERS COMPENSATION CLAIMS ADMINISTRATOR GOODWILL OF CENTRAL AND NORTHERN ARIZONA — 2018 - 2019

- Case management for all liability and workers compensation claims.
- Provide legal assistance to inside counsel, including preparing legal material packets.
- Work as part of the finance department and specialize in risk management and cost reduction.
- Extensive knowledge of Arizona Workers Compensation Law.
- Perform OSHA 300 form reporting for all locations.

REPORT DEPARTMENT SUPERVISOR/CHIEF EDITOR PREMIER PHYSICIANS MANAGEMENT COMPANY — 2015 - 2018

- Schedule, planning and performing Supervisory tasks and full oversight of the department and its employees.
- Multi-tasking and prioritizing reports while also delegating within the department
- Report editing for QME/AME/IME doctors', evaluations, and supplemental reports
- Verify insurance eligibility, provide claims information, dissect cover letters
- Provide claims information to workers compensation insurances
- Use of electronic health record software programs
- Organize depositions for attorneys' offices and workers compensation insurances
- Med/Legal information sharing systems and account management
- Time management to meet report deadlines
- Direct interaction with attorneys and insurance offices
- Editor in Chief of all Medical-Legal Reports
- Extensive knowledge of the California Workers Compensation System/ Labor Codes/C.C.R's

•

SAMUEL R. TORRES

torressam333@gmail.com (909) 531-1233

PROJECT MANAGER INDIO EMERGENCY MEDICAL GROUP, INC. - 2009-2012

- Streamlined patient data management by implementing EHR/EMR system
- Provided customer service to patients while scheduling appointments
- Knowledge of all medical insurances, ICD10/CPT/POS/CCI codes
- Payment collection and updating accounts in practice management software
- Knowledge of Urgent Care front office operations and medical practices
- Working with patient database and data management systems

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Management & Supervisory Experience	Proficient in Spanish	Medical Billing/ Collections Experience
Passion for learning new technologies	Customer Service	Honesty and integrity
	Computer software/	Transcription Experience
Online Sharing Platform Organization	Microsoft Office Learn new technologies	Punctuality
Organizational Skills	quickly.	

REFERENCES

- Terry McBride, IEMG/Supervisor 760-322-1201 <u>terry@iemginc.com</u>
- Nicholas Lopez, PPMC Office Manager 760-569-5512